Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Wesley W. Posvar, Administrative Files, 1967-1991 UA.2.10.1967-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Academic Year 1976/77, X.
  - University Boards, Committees and Memberships, 1976-1977; 3.0.
    - Official Memberships, 1976-1977; 3.6.
      - Presbyterian-University Hospital Executive Committee Meetings, October 13, 1976-January 13, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 3.6.6d)
      - Presbyterian-University Hospital Executive Committee Meetings, February 10 - May 12, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 3.6.6e)
      - WQED Board Meetings and Fundraising (Box 14, Folder 3.6.9)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), "The dangers of penetration by covert agents of the CIA on campuses", November 12, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 3.7)
    - Institutional Memberships, 1976-1977; 3.7.
      - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 14, Folder 3.7.1)
      - MPC Corporation (Box 14, Folder 3.7.3)
      - Pennsylvania Association of Colleges and Universities (PACU) (Box 14, Folder 3.7.4)
      - PACU Meetings (Box 15, Folder 3.7.4a)
      - PACU, "US Foreign Policy: Principles for Defining the National Interest," a Public Agenda Foundation Report, and Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 3.7.4b)
      - Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education (PCHE) (Box 15, Folder 3.7.5)
      - PCHE Center for Urban Research Questionnaires (Box 15, Folder 3.7.5a)
      - University Health Center (UHC) (Box 15, Folder 3.7.8)
        Administrators Committee Meeting Minutes; Proposed new affiliation agreements between the University and the Health Center Hospitals, February 17, 1977; Report of the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Land Use Planning, September 7, 1976; UHCP, Office of Educational Development and Research, General Information; and "Department of Anesthesiology and Critical Care Medicine Program, the First 15 Years, 1961-1976."
      - UHC Pamphlets and Medical Staff and Land Bank Committee Meeting Minutes (Box 15, Folder 3.7.8a)
      - UHC (Box 15, Folder 3.7.8b)
      - Montefiore Hospital Situation (Box 16, Folder 3.7.8c)
      - UHC Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, March 15 - June 2, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 3.7.8d)
      - UHC Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, December 8, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 3.7.8e)
      - UHC Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, October 14, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 3.7.8f)
      - UHC Agreements & Statements (Box 16, Folder 3.7.8f.1)
      - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), Dr. Spauling Elected to AAUP Council, March 4, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 3.7.9)
      - Women's Association Annual Report and Posvar Speech (Box 16, Folder 3.7.13)
      - Association of American Universities (AAU) (Box 16, Folder 3.7.14-3.7.14a)
        Establishment of the Office of Energy Research in the New Department of Energy; Federal Legislation Regulating Recombinant DNA Research, May 1977; Dr. Posvar agrees to serve on AAU Committee on Research, March 1977; Meeting of College and University Heads with President Carter, February 19, 1977; Graduate Education; Analysis of Plans for Reorganization of HEW, December 17, 1976; and AAU Meetings.
      - National Council of Christians & Jews (NCCJ) Annual Brotherhood Awards Dinner (Box 17, Folder 3.7.15)
      - Committee on Urban Public Universities (CUPU) (Box 17, Folder 3.7.16)
    - Chancellor's Staff Meetings, 1976-1977; 3.8.
      - General Chancellor's Staff Meetings, 3.8.0.
      - Senior Staff Meetings, 3.8.1.
        - Senior Staff Meetings and Action Items, May 3 - June 17, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 3.8.1)
        - Senior Staff Meetings and Action Items, October 4, 1976 - February 15, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 3.8.1b)
        - Senior Staff Meetings and Action Items, July 19 - September 23, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 3.8.1c)
      - Administrative Staff, 3.8.2.
        - Administrative Staff Meetings, October 28, 1976 - June 18, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 3.8.2)
        - Administrative Staff Meetings and Action Items, July 14, 1976 - May 20, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 3.8.2a)
    - Affirmative Action, 1976-1977; 3.10.
      - Affirmative Action - General (Box 18, Folder 3.1)
        Title IX and Title IX Assurance; The University-wide Affirmative Action Committee will be reconstituted to form three subcommittees representing faculty, staff and students, April 22, 1977; and Paper, "University Affirmative Action Policy in Regard to the Recruitment, Selection, Development and Evaluation of Faculty and Staff Employees of the University of Pittsburgh."
  - Administration and Planning, 1976-1977; 4.0.
    - Administration and Planning - General, 1976-1977; 4.0.
      - Oakland Neighborhood and Building Projects (Box 18, Folder 4.0.)
        Oakland Improvement Corp., July 1976; Professional Quadrangle, April 4, 1976; and Campus Map, Perspective Map and Architectural Model Listing, July 20, 1976.
    - Facilities and Physical Plant Operations, 1976-1977; 4.1.
      - Facilities and Physical Plant Operations - General, 4.1.0.
        - Physical Plant Operations Report and FY1977 Repair and Renovation Projects (Box 18, Folder 4.1)
      - Operations, 4.1.1.
        - Operations - General (Box 18, Folder 4.1.1-4.1.1a)
          Folder 4.1.1
          Evening Student Parking and Transportation Study and Final Recommendations; Considerations and Procedures for Dealing with Campus Disruptions or Protests; Cathedral of Learning has been listed on the National Register of Historic Places with certificate and correspondence from Pittsburgh History and Landmarks Foundation; Renovation work at 231-233 Oakland Avenue; Facility Alterations and Renovations, April 27, 1977; Virgil Cantini Sculpture with sketches, April 21, 1977; Webster Hall, April 20, 1977; Communications Taping System, March 31, 1977; Health and Safety Organization, Enforcement, and Policy; Merger of Administrative Systems with the Academic Computing Center, February 23, 1977; Book Store Advisory Board, February 18, 1977; Bellefield Boiler Plant and Beliefield System, February 1977; University Seals, February 10, 1977; and Smoking in Classrooms and Places of Assembly, September 15, 1976. Folder 4.1.1a
          Energy Conservation and Utilities Management, June 28, 1977; Physical Facilities Master Plan, May 31, 1977; Professional Quadrangle Cornerstone, April 28, 1977; Dedication of Forbes Quadrangle & Nursing Building, September 26, 1977; Approval for renovation project of Life Sciences in Clapp, Langley, and Crawford Halls, November 4, 1976; Review of paintings in the Law Building, November 10, 1976; Christmas Trees and Christmas Decorations; and Operations Board of Visitors.
        - Energy and Environment Committee, Tuition Remission, Energy Crisis, and Parking (Box 18, Folder 4.1.1b)
        - Minority Business, Mervis, Tuition Increases, Management Review Teams, and Governor's Review Team (Box 19, Folder 4.1.1c)
    - Finance, 1976-1977; 4.2.
      - Financial Report for Year Ending, June 30, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 4.2.3)
    - Treasurer, 1976-1977; 4.3.
      - Registrar - General (Box 19, Folder 4.3.1)
      - Spring and Winter Term Enrollments (Box 19, Folder 4.3.1.1)
    - Planning and Budget, 1976-1977; 4.4.
      - Planning and Budget - General, 4.4.0.
        - Planning and Budget - General (Box 19, Folder 4.4-4.4c)
          Folder 4.4
          Meeting with Paul Hammond regarding institutional planning and policy, June 20, 1977; Explosion at Langley Hall, June 13, 1977; Planning and renovation of the construction work in the research laboratories (6/3/77). Physical Planning and Development, June 3, 1977; FY 1978 Operating Budget; Meeting with Max Abramovitz, May 1977; and "An Analysis of Undergraduate Grades Given at the University of Pittsburgh, 1968-1969 to 1975-1976."
          Folder 4.4a
          Physical Facilities Master Plan, May 31, 1977; Proposal to Reconstitute the Institute for Higher Education, May 14, 1977; Memo regarding Animal Care Facility; and Responses to Questions of Members of the House Appropriations Committee Regarding the University of Pittsburgh FY 1978 Budget Request, April 25, 1977.
          Folder 4.4b
          Proposal for VIP Box at Pitt Stadium; FY 1977 Repair and Renovation Projects; and Planning and Resource Management System Procedures Manual.
          Folder 4.4c
          Annual Report, Office of Planning and Budget, August 30, 1976; Management Information System (MIS) Progress Report, August 16, 1976; and Pitt's industrial security program is in conformity with the requirements of the Industrial Security Manual, August 8, 1976.
        - Planning and Budget Papers (Box 19, Folder 4.4d-4.4e)
          Folder 4.4d
          "The University of Pittsburgh, 1976-1990"; "Physical Resources Information System, User Reference Guide," December 1975; "Analysis of Preliminary Demographic Projections for Western Pennsylvania, 1975-1990"; "Impact of Center for Urban Research's Funding on University of Pittsburgh Enrollment Projections"; and "A Program for National Distinction: A Third Center of Service," July 1976.
          Folder 4.4e
          "The University of Pittsburgh, 1976-1990," with The University Plan, 1976; "Advising, Counseling and Placement Services"; and "Evening Student Parking, Transportation and Security Study," December 1976.
        - Budget (Box 20, Folder 4.4f)
        - Budget and Learning Information Center (Box 20, Folder 4.4g)
        - University Planning Advisory Council, University Plan, Animal Care Facilities, and Retrenchment and Program Termination (Box 20, Folder 4.4h)
        - Planning and Budget Booklets (Box 20, Folder 4.4i)
          Budget Presentation 1976-1977 and 1977-1978; Response of the University of Pittsburgh to the Joint State Government Commission Analysis of Faculty Output and Salary Costs of State-Related Universities, June 1976; and "A Study of the Academic Performance of Regional Campus Relocates and Transfers from Other Colleges and Universities at the Oakland Campus of the University of Pittsburgh."
      - Collective Bargaining, 4.4.1.
        - Pitt Professional Union and Academic Collective Bargaining Information Service (Box 20, Folder 4.4.1a)
      - Strategic Planning, 4.4.2.
        - Strategic Planning - General (Box 21, Folder 4.4.2)
          "Restructuring Pitt's Academic Program: A Radical Alternative"; Summary of School Responses to the "University of Pittsburgh, 1976-1990," March 1977; and Strategic planning from Provost's Area, Health Related Professions, School of Medicine, Public Health, Dental Medicine, and University Center for Urban Research.
      - Long Range Objectives, 4.4.3.
        - Policy Manual and Meeting Minutes (Box 21, Folder 4.4.3)
      - Space Utilization, 4.4.4.
        - Space Allocations and Relocations (Box 21, Folder 4.4.4)
    - Personnel, 1976-1977; 4.5.
      - Personnel - General (Box 21, Folder 4.5)
        Grievance Policy Statement and Proposal for Staff Ombudsman, September 2, 1976; Announcement of Forthcoming Holiday Observances, January 5, 1977; Health Benefit Programs; Testing Program for Clerical/Secretaries Applicants for Employment; and Proposed Affirmative Action Committee for Staff Employees.
    - Security, 1976-1977; 4.7.
      - Security - General (Box 22, Folder 4.7)
        Campus Police Recruitment, March 3, 1977; Campus Police Telephone Recording System, February 24, 1977; and Report of the Chancellor's Administrative Study Group on Campus Security, October 11, 1976.
      - University of Pittsburgh Police Department Manual, May 9, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 4.7a)
      - University of Pittsburgh Police Department Statistical Report and "University of Pittsburgh Campus Community Security: A Program for Progress" (Box 22, Folder 4.7b)
    - Computer Center, 1976-1977; 4.8.
      - Computer Center - General (Box 22, Folder 4.8)
        The unification of administrative and academic computing, December 20, 1976; Mellon Grant, May 24, 1977; Cooperation between CMU and Pitt; and Meeting Minutes.
  - Chancellor's Office, 1976-1977; 5.0.
    - Chancellor's Office - General, 1976-1977; 5.0.
      - Chancellor's Office (Box 22, Folder 5.0.)
        Comments on Commencement, April 26, 1976; Taping Interview with Lando, Inc.; and Memos for the Record, to Staff, and from Dr. E.E. Bozik to University personnel.
    - Office Correspondence, 1976-1977; 5.1.
      - Office Correspondence - General (Box 22, Folder 5.1)
        Guidelines for Control of Correspondence Destined for the Office of the Chancellor, February 27, 1977; General Guidelines for the Management and Operation of the Office of the Chancellor, effective September 7, 1976; and Suggested Physical Space Reorganization, Office of the Chancellor, March 9, 1977.
      - Letters of Condolence Sent from the Chancellor's Office (Box 22, Folder 5.1.1)
      - Courtesy Letters (Box 22, Folder 5.1.2)
      - Letters Sent by the Chancellor's Office (Box 23, Folder 5.1.2a)
      - Thank You Letters (Box 23, Folder 5.1.2.1)
      - Thank You Letters Sent and Received by the Chancellor's Office (Box 23, Folder 5.1.2.1a)
      - Congratulations (Box 23, Folder 5.1.2.2)
      - Accepted Invitations (Box 23, Folder 5.1.3)
      - Invitations Accepted for University and Outside Functions (Box 23, Folder 5.1.3a)
      - Invitations - Regrets (Box 24, Folder 5.1.4)
      - Regrets to Invitations for University and Outside Functions (Box 24, Folder 5.1.4a)
      - Invitations Extended by the Chancellor's Office (Box 24, Folder 5.1.5-5.1.5a)
      - Invitations for University and Outside Functions (Box 24, Folder 5.1.5b)
      - Invitations for University and Outside Functions (Box 25, Folder 5.1.5c)
      - Statements from Chancellor's Office (Box 25, Folder 5.1.9)
        Includes "The State of the University, 1977" from the University of Pittsburgh Association Lunch, May 18, 1977; "Capital Financing for Health Facilities," November 19, 1976; Opening Remarks, Cuba Conference, November 15, 1976; Dedication of Elizabeth Nesbitt Room, October 29, 1976; Remarks Before Incoming Freshmen Orientation Ceremonies, School of Medicine, September 7, 1976; and Testimony on the Proposed Budget for the National Science Foundation for Fiscal Year 1978, March 3, 1977.
      - Speeches Delivered by Chancellor Posvar (Box 25, Folder 5.1.10)
      - Telegrams Sent and Received by the Chancellor's Office (Box 25, Folder 5.1.11)
  - Program Development and Public Affairs, 1976-1977; 6.0.
    - Program Development and Public Affairs - General, 1976-1977; 6.0.
      - Program Development and Public Affairs (Box 25, Folder 6.0.)
        H. Jerome Wharton Memorial; Gertrude and Philip Hoffman Judaic Library, August 16, 1976; "Planning and Resource Management Systems Procedures Manual, 1976" booklet; and WTAE-TV (Channel 4) editorial about Center for Arms Control and International Security Studies.
    - Public Affairs, 1976-1977; 6.1.
      - Public Affairs - General, 6.1.0.
        - Public Affairs (Box 25, Folder 6.1-6.1a)
          Folder 6.1
          Purchase of Broadcast Advertising for University Programs; Request approval to install signs at three locations along the Pennsylvania Turnpike; Recognition of Lou Mason; The Audubon Double Elephant Folio: Birds of America, February 8, 1977; conversation with Mr. Norval Reese, February 3, 1977; The U.S. Jaycees announce the opening of nominations for the 1978 Ten Outstanding Young Men of America; Dedication of the Mazeroski plaque from Forbes Field at the Center Field Plaza; and the Scientific papers of the late Dr. Joshua Tabatchnik.
          Folder 6.1a
          Presentation of the Marshall Peace Award to Kurt Waldheim, June 12, 1977.
        - United Nations Visit to Pennsylvania, June 12, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 6.1b)
      - Gifts and Grants, 6.1.1.
        - Mulert Memorial Fund and the Heinz, Hillman and Pittsburgh Foundations (Box 26, Folder 6.1.1b)
    - Alumni Affairs, 1976-1977; 6.2.
      - Alumni Affairs - General, 6.2.0.
        - Alumni Publications and Events (Box 26, Folder 6.2)
      - Annual Giving Fund and United Way, 6.2.1.
        - United Way/Annual Giving Fund (Box 26, Folder 6.2.1)
        - United Way/Annual Giving Fund (Box 27, Folder 6.2.1a)
      - Capital Campaign, 6.2.3.
        - "Dollars That Make the Difference" Campaign (Box 27, Folder 6.2.3)
    - Governmental Relations, 1976-1977; 6.3.
      - Governmental Relations - General (Box 27, Folder 6.3)
        Meeting with Congressman Hawkins, June 10, 1977; Energy Bill, May 27, 1977; American Association of State Colleges and Universities' Office of Federal Programs, May 17, 1977; Gerontology Programs, April 12, 1977; The Snyder Report, March 14, 1977; Results of Flood's Subcommittee Mark-up on Health Program; Citizens Advisory Council Annual Report, 1975-1976; and Sunshine Law, October 19, 1976.
      - D.C. Congressional Luncheon (Box 27, Folder 6.3a)
      - Legislative Office for Research Liaison (LORL) and Northeast Governor's Conference (Box 27, Folder 6.3b)
      - Commonwealth Relations (Box 27, Folder 6.3.1)
      - Federal Government Relations (Box 27, Folder 6.3.2)
      - Local Government Relations (Box 28, Folder 6.3.3)
    - American Assembly, 1976-1977; 6.4.
      - American Assembly Regional Meetings and Booklets (Box 28, Folder 6.4)
    - Office of Cultural and Educational Exchange, 1976-1977; 6.5.
      - Nationality Rooms (Box 28, Folder 6.5)
        Special Thanks to Dr. Posvar and Dr. A.C. Van Dusen for their roles in making possible the commemoration of the Nationality Rooms 50th Anniversary; Minister of Culture and Sciences of Greece will send three replicas of ancient Greek works of arts to university for American Bicentennial celebration; Bulgarian Nationality Room, July 1976; and African Heritage Room.
    - News and Publications, 1976-1977; 6.6.
      - News and Publications - General (Box 28, Folder 6.6)
      - Clippings (Box 28, Folder 6.6.1)
      - Pitt Releases and Pitt Updates (Box 28, Folder 6.6.2)
      - Pitt News (Box 28, Folder 6.6.3)
      - FAS Gazette (Box 28, Folder 6.6.4)
      - Annual Report of the Chancellor (Box 28, Folder 6.6.6)
      - EDUCOM (Box 28, Folder 6.6.7)
      - University Times (Box 28, Folder 6.6.9)
    - University Press, 1976-1977; 6.7.
      - University Press Pamphlet on Books for Spring and Summer 1977 (Box 28, Folder 6.7)
    - Office of Urban and Community Services (OUCS), 1976-1977; 6.8.
    - Office of Special Events, 1976-1977; 6.9.
      - Office of Special Events - General (Box 28, Folder 6.9)
        Parents' Weekend 1977; Music for the Christmas Season; The need for an additional assistant director in the Office of Special Events, March 28, 1977; and Impressions of an Ideal Office of Special Events, November 16, 1976.
  - Student Affairs, 1976-1977; 7.0.
    - Student Affairs - General, 1976-1977; 7.0.
      - Reports and Pamphlets (Box 29, Folder 7.0.)
        Draft Report of the Task Force on Recruitment and Admissions; "A Proposal to Permit Part-Time Evening Students to Utilize University-Owned Parking Facilities During the Evening Hours"; and "Guidelines on Academic Integrity, Student and Faculty Obligations and Hearing Procedures," effective September 1, 1976.
    - Student Affairs, 1976-1977; 7.1.
      - Student Affairs - General (Box 29, Folder 7.1)
        Task Force on Black Students; Problems Related to Legislation; Student Voter Registration, March 11, 1977; Boy Scout Jamboree; and "Student Code of Conduct and Judicial Procedures," effective September 1976.
      - Dean of Student Activities (Box 29, Folder 7.1.1.1)
        Correspondence regarding Beer Festival; University of Pittsburgh's first annual Monte Carlo Night, March 17, 1977; Draft policy on the use of the Cathedral of Learning Commons Room by student organizations, February 10, 1977; and New Director for Office of Student Activities Mr. Willard F. Heaps, effective January 16, 1977.
      - Dean of Admissions and Student Aid (Box 29, Folder 7.1.2)
        Fall/Winter Work Study Program; Select Student Aid Statistics, Basic Grant and Campus-Based Programs; Black Action Society, Student Aid and Check Disbursements; and Dr. Charles R. Dees resigns as Associate Dean of Admissions and Student Aid, effective September 30, 1976.
      - Weekly Admissions Reports (Box 29, Folder 7.1.2.1)
      - University Housing (Box 29, Folder 7.1.3)
      - Student Placement (Box 29, Folder 7.1.4)
    - Organizations, 1976-1977; 7.2.
      - Organizations - General (Box 29, Folder 7.2)
        University Review Board Amendments, June 29, 1977; American Cancer Society Letter thanking fraternities and sororities for their Greek Week effort, March 14, 1977; Men's Glee Club performs at West Point and Ladycliff College, February 1977; Correspondence regarding Black Action Society; Project SAD (Sigmas Attack Defects) sponsored by Phi Sigma Fraternity, October 13, 1976; Funding of Student Groups; America's First College Auto Racing Team; and Grievances and Complaints against Fraternity Houses on Bayard Street.
      - Student Affairs Advisory Committee (Box 29, Folder 7.2.2)
      - Student Government (Box 29, Folder 7.2.3)
    - University Activity for Students, 1976-1977; 7.4.
      - Commencement (Box 29, Folder 7.4.1)
        Program Script, Commencement Convocation, April 24, 1977; Itinerary for Commencement; Commencement Luncheon and Ceremony; S. David Freeman, speaker; and Schedule of the Day, April 15, 1977.
      - Homecoming and Parents Weekend (Box 30, Folder 7.4.2)
      - Honors Convocation (Box 30, Folder 7.4.3-7.4.3a)
        Dr. Baruch S. Blumberg, The Institute for Cancer Research, is guest speaker for Honors Convocation.
    - ROTC and Veterans Affairs, 1976-1977; 7.5.
      - ROTC and Veterans Affairs - General (Box 30, Folder 7.5)
        Status of Detachment 730 Air Force ROTC, April 11, 1977; Evaluation Status of the Army ROTC Program; Position of Professor of Aerospace Science; Appointment of Coordinator of Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; and Veteran Student Enrollment Verification Report.
    - Scholarships and Awards, 1976-1977; 7.6.
      - Scholarships and Awards - General (Box 30, Folder 7.6)
        The Rhodes Scholarship; Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation; Chancellor's Undergraduate Teaching Fellowships; Chancellor's Scholars; National Merit Scholars; and Honors Programs.
    - International Students, 1976-1977; 7.7.
      - International Students - General (Box 30, Folder 7.7)
        Current Procedures for Foreign Graduate Admission to the University of Pittsburgh, February 7, 1977; Mr. Ralph S. Morrison appointed Director, Office of International Student Services, effective September 27, 1976; and "Directory of Foreign Students, Faculty, Research and Statistics of Enrollment, 1976-1977."
  - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977; 8.0.
    - Pennsylvania Public Television Network Memo and Carnegie Magazine Article (Box 30, Folder 8.0.)
    - State Board of Education (Box 30, Folder 8.1)
      New membership list for each task force, June 8, 1977; Biennial Report to the Governor and the General Assembly, January 1977; Resolution of the State Board of Education recommending to the Governor funding levels for higher education in FY 1978, passed November 12, 1976; and House Bill 2494, the "Sunset Law," June 23, 1976.
    - State Board of Education: Master Plan, Southwest Pennsylvania Higher Education Council, and Higher Education Circular (Box 30, Folder 8.1a)
    - State Board of Education: Commonwealth Universities (Box 30, Folder 8.1b)
    - State Board of Education: Higher Education Council (Box 30, Folder 8.1c)
    - State Board of Education: Task Force on Finance (Box 31, Folder 8.1d)
    - State Board of Education: Legislation (Box 31, Folder 8.1e)
    - State Board of Education, Administration (Box 31, Folder 8.1f)
    - State Board of Education: Cooperative Programs with Local Colleges (Box 31, Folder 8.1.1)